水 形 物 语
要吃点什么吗？
太美了
谢谢
一个S是Mardi Gras 意思是狂欢节
坦塔罗斯：源自希腊神话，喻指能够看目标却永远达不到目标的痛苦
什么建议
我确定
它不是垃圾
我不要
祝你好运
鸡蛋
音乐
你还好吧？
暗号...
“魂断猎鹰喙”
走吧
鲍勃!
近来如何
我在这狗屁水泥屋子里
像个傻子一样等了你足足一个小时
每次都是在这个烂餐厅接头！
我会改地儿的
但是你没有
告诉我们
"鲍勃"
叫我迪米特里
同志们
我不是"鲍勃"
这是什么?
迪米特里
解剖学笔记...
还有...
实验室结构图
项目的研究地点
我们从这抽身所需要的一切
都在这了
我会向上级汇报的
我们必须得尽快把这事搞定
米哈尔科夫...
这个生物...
我觉得它能够
与人交流
交流?
是的 与人交流
我有足够证据证明
它是种高智商物种
它会识别
它会识别...
语言...
能对音乐作出反应...
你能把这些
也报告给上级吗？
我会的
现在...
吃吧 迪米特里
他们把这道菜叫做...
海鲜...
及牛排
海陆大餐
煮好的龙虾放在这
嗞喇嗞喇的
但是有点...
过软了...
还太甜了
他很孤独
非常孤独
念出我的手语
你根本没在听
重复一遍
重复
念出我的手语
如果我们
什么也不做
那我们也算不上人类
莫斯科方面不会支持你的计划
为什么?
风险太大
时间太紧
什么?！
我们只有两个选项 迪米特里
其一...
你想办法推迟计划
至少一周
但他们明天就要实施了
所以...
只剩下
第二个选择
以色列炸弹
你把它安在保险丝盒子上
然后会停电十分钟
没有监控 没有阻碍
然后...
你把这个给它注射
注射
杀了它
毁了它
你还好吗?
我来到这个国家
尽我所能的学习
既是一个爱国者...
也是科学家
我们还有许多可以学习的
我们不需要学
我们只要让美国人
没机会学
书名：《积极思考出奇效》
会下雨的
你受伤了 你流血了
请进
你的撤离文件...
他们快准备好了
首先 我有个问题
是吗? 请问吧
你们想来点...
黄油蛋糕吗?
好的 谢谢
你注射了...
那个研究对象之后
你怎么处理尸体的?
我很好奇
我进行了解剖
没什么价值
列宁曾经说过
死鱼是没有价值的
列宁
说过这个?
蛋糕不错！
你有牛奶吗?
也许...
也许是...
你记错了
等我们的回信
不会很久的
《伯南扎的牛仔》：1959年首播，是美国第一部彩色西部连续剧
撤离...
已经安排好了
老地方
四十八小时之后
四十八小时?
四十八小时
真是倾盆大雨啊
今天没有暗号吗?
不要 不要 同志...
不要...
不要 求你了！
你
和我
在一起
不 没有我
没有我
关于她的故事
If I spoke about it.
如果要讲的话
If I did.
我要怎么说呢
What would I tell you?
我在想
I wonder.
故事发生在什么时候呢？
Would I tell you about the time?
似乎 发生在很久以前了
It happened a long time ago- It seems...
那位王子当政的最后几天
In the last days of a fair Prince's reign...
我们还是先来讲讲那个地方吧
Or would I tell you about the place?
那是一座小城 靠近海岸
A small city near the coast
与世隔绝
but far from everything else...
还能给你讲点什么呢
Or, I don't know.
要么跟你讲讲她的故事吧
Would I tell you about her?
公主无法说话
The princess without voice
或许我该提醒你
Or perhaps I would just warn you
这些故事是真实的
about the truth of these facts
这是一个悲欢离合的故事
and the tale of love and loss
还有那个
and the monster
试图摧毁一切的恶魔
that tried to destroy it all...
荷达克大人
My Lord Hedak.
你感到烦恼
So, you are troubled.
说出来吧
Tell me.
我
I have...
我有罪
I have sinned.
我触犯了上帝
I've offended the god.
荷达克大人 我是个罪人
I'm deep in sin, my Lord Hedak.
我自有判断
Let me judge of that.
我对祭祀仪式 有所怀疑
I've doubted the ceremony of the sacrifice.
警报声把你吵醒了么
Did the sirens wake you up?
那个巧克力工厂 着火了
It was a fire. The chocolate factory.
你闻到这味了么 我的天
You smell that? Oh my...
烤熟的可可
Toasted cocoa.
塞翁失马 焉知非福
Tragedy and delight-- Hand in hand.
亲爱的
Oh dear child.
要是没你在这照顾我 我就会日渐消瘦了
I'd waste away if you weren't here looking after me.
众所周知 我可是很耐饿的 看这个
I am the proverbial starving. Watch this.
看着楼梯舞
Bojangles, the stair dance.
这舞蹈挺难学的
That's so hard.
卡格尼就做到了
Cagney did it. Different but beautiful.
我也想学这舞蹈
I want to do that too.
好呀 准备好了么
All right. Are you ready?
- 好了 - 来吧
- Yep. - Come on.
艾丽莎
Elisa.
下次你来交房租的时候
Next time you're going to bring the rent,
我想让你留下来看这部圣经主题的电影
I want you to stay and see the bible movie, huh.
我这...我这有两张免费电影票
I got... I got two free tickets here.
把你的邻居查尔斯也带上 他是个好人
You bring your neighbor Charles. He's a good boy.
或者你要看喜剧片? 现在没几个人看电影了
Find a movie in comedy? Nobody's coming to the theater, huh.
我会给你提供免费的爆米花和苏打水的
I can throw you a free popcorn and soda.
哦不 我的天 那里应该放两个S啊
Oh no, for God's sake! There's two "S' there.
快点 放两个S
Come on. Two "S". Mardi Grass. Mardi Grass.
艾丽莎 快来 快点来
Elisa, come on. Come here already!
- 你要学会按时上班啊 - 嘿 你干什么呢
- You gotta learn to be on time. - Hey, what you doing?
- 就这么让她插队么 蠢货 - 少管闲事
- Look her in, Dummy. - Leave her alone, woman.
我帮她排了队的
I was keepin' her place.
我会检举你们的 我会来找你和这哑巴的麻烦的
I get reported. I come after you and the mute.
你去啊 尤兰达
You do that, Yolanda.
你去啊
You do that.
我这脚 真是疼死我了
My feet are already killin' me.
我那天晚上走之前 给布鲁斯特做了面包热狗卷
I made Brewster pigs in the blanket tonight before leavin'.
我的天 他就这么吃完了
Boy, he just ate 'em up.
没说谢谢 吃的时候也没发出声音
No thank-yous, no yum-yums, not a peep-
冷峻的就像一座墓碑那样
Man is silent as the grave.
如果放屁声是他对我的奉承
But if farts were flattery
那他简直堪比文豪莎士比亚了
Honey, he'd be Shakespeare.
然后我回家 给他做早餐
Then I get home and I make him breakfast.
鸡蛋 培根 还有烤面包片加黄油
Eggs, bacon and buttered toast.
我还要给烤面包双面都抹上黄油 艾丽莎 搞得就像他是我儿子一样
I butter the man's toast, Elisa. Both sides-As if he was a child...
他甚至连一声谢谢都不会说
And I don't even get a “Thank You”
你懂的感恩 因为你是受过教育的
You'd be grateful, because you are an educated woman.
但是我家的那位嘛 身上只散发出一种野性的魅力
But my Brewster, all he had gone for him was animal magnetism back in the day
原来还挺吸引我的
And workin' awhile.
我的天
What in the same hell?
露！
Lou!
你们这帮小子介不介意把垃圾都丢到桶里
You boys mind puttin' the trash in the can?
垃圾就应该丢到该丢的地方去
That's what it's that for.
真是难以置信 垃圾就应该丢到该丢的地方去
Hard to believe, uh? That's what it's that for.
- 好 好 抱歉 泽尔达 - 我不知道他们整天在干什么
- Alright. Alright. Sorry Zelda, sorry. - I don't know what they're doin'.
要我说 你们真是搞得一塌糊涂
Makin' a goddamn mess, in what I'd say.
- 泽尔达 别聊天了 - 是 长官
- Zelda, stop the chatting please. - Yes sir.
- 没有必要说那些话 - 抱歉 弗莱明先生
- There's no call for the blaspheme. - Sorry, Mr. Fleming.
占用各位一点时间
A moment of your time.
今天有一队新的研究人员和研究对象要来到我们T-4设施
Today, we are receiving a new team and asset here in T-4.
这位是罗伯特·霍夫斯德勒 从加尔维斯顿调过来
This is Dr. Robert Hoffstetler, from our system facility in Galveston.
我不是想虚张声势 夸大其词什么的
Now, I don't want to bolster or overstate the matter but uh
这个可能是目前这个设施里
this may very well be the most sensitive asset
最重要的研究对象了
ever to be housed in this facility
- 旅途如何？- 还行
- How was your trip? - Fine.
- 安保人员在哪？- 请稍后
- Who's security here? - Just one moment please.
- 安保人员在哪？- 欢迎来到T-4设施 长官
Security. Who's security here? - Welcome to T-4, sir.
是 长官 我是弗兰明 这里的安保负责人
Yes, sir. I am Flemington, Head of Security...
把闲杂人赶出去
Get them out.
帮我把这圆柱箱推进压缩机里
Help me move the cylinder into the compressor!
搬过来 搬过来
Bring it here. Bring it here.
艾丽莎 艾丽莎 快走吧
Elisa! Elisa, come on.
那里是什么情况 你看到了么？
What goes on in this place? Did you see that?
是的 我搞了些装饰品 看起来怎么样
Yes, I'm wearing the hair piece. How's is it look like?
小心车
Careful of the car.
严格来说那不是什么装饰品 是假发
It's not a hair piece. It's a toupee.
假发是不会脱落的 懂了吧
It's eternal, see?
坦塔罗斯难求一死
Tantalus never achieved the escape of death.
树枝上的果实总是放在他够不着的地方
There's a fruit on the branches was just always out of his reach.
每次他弯腰喝水的时候溪水里的水就退了
And the water in the stream receded every time he stooped down to drink.
这就是为什么我们今天说这些话
And so that's why we say things today like
看那些诱人的馅饼
Look at those tantalizing pies.
谢谢 你会回来的 对吧？
Thank you, ya'll come back, y'heah?
是的 早餐吃馅饼 相信我吧
Yes, pies for breakfast! Just trust me on this.
嘿 各位 欢迎来到迪克西·道格馅饼店
Hey folks, welcome to Dixie Doug's.
我之前在这见过你 对吧？
- I've seen you here before, right?
是的 我其实已经来过好几次了
- Yes, I've been here a couple of times as a matter of fact.
专点莱姆派吧？
- Partial to key lime pie?
是的 来两份
- Oh yeah, I am. Two to go.
别纠结啦
Just go with it, please.
额 我就好这口
Uh. I-uh. It's a craving I indulge in.
吃这个虽然对我的身体没什么好处 我喜欢的东西都不...
It can't possibly be good for me. Nothing that I like is...
这是很好的馅饼 酸橙味
No, no. It's a mighty fine pie, key lime.
你是鼎鼎有名的迪克西·道格么？
You would happen to be the famous Dixie Doug himself, huh?
当然不是 馅饼是全国派送的
- Heck, no. Pies are trucked throughout the country.
- 他们管这叫“特许经营” 明白了吧？- 哦
- They call it uh, “franchising”, see? - Oh.
他们给我们提供搅拌机 挂上他们的招牌 就那个“馅饼小子” 是我们的吉祥物
They give us the spinners, the signage. That there's “Pie Boy” our mascot.
我一般不提这些的
I don't talk like that.
- 我从渥太华来的 -不会吧
- I'm from Ottawa. - No.
我完全买下它了
I completely bought it.
“这个馅饼真不错”
“That's-a-great-a-pie”
那个小个子男人 他是意大利人吗？
The.. The Little guy. Is he supposed to be Italian?
我猜是的
I guess so.
真聪明
That was very clever.
你们都回来了？
Y'all come back now, y'heah?
“你们都回来了”
“Y'all come back now”
你觉得他说这话是认真的吗？
Do you think he meant it?
他注意到我了 你听到了他说的那些
He had noticed me. You heard that.
这个馅饼真恶心
This pie is rather sordid.
不要吐出来 下次去的时候 我们试试其他味道
Don't spit it out. Next time we go, well try different flavor.
待会儿再吃
Save it for later.
上帝啊 换个台吧 我不想看那个台
Dear God, change that awfulness. I do not want to see that.
我不想看那个台
I do not want to see it.
这个台还行 这个台还行
That's better. That's better.
哦 看贝蒂！
Oh. Look at Betty!
年轻貌美
Oh. To be young and beautiful
如果时光可以倒流
If I could go back,
回到我18岁的时候
to when I was eighteen
我什么都不知道 我会给自己一点建议
I didn't know anything about anything. I'd give myself a bit of advice.
比如说 保护好牙齿 多做点爱
I would say. Take better care of your teeth and fuck-a lot more.
真是好建议
That's very good advice.
我漂亮的宝贝
Pretty baby of mine.
看看这个
Will you look at this?
看看
Look.
这里有我们国家最聪明的一群家伙 而他们却在这地板上到处撒尿
Some of the best minds in our country peeing all over the floor in this here facility.
嗯
Mh-mh-mhm.
连天花板上都是尿渍！
There's pee freckles on the ceiling!
他们怎么撒上去的？
How do they get it up there?
你估计 他们下面那玩意得有多大啊？
Just how big a target do they need, you figure?
他们已经做了充足的练习 这是肯定的
They get enough practice that's for sure.
我的布鲁斯特
My Brewster,
可没人觉得他聪明
no one ever called him a great mind,
但是
but...
就算他 他都有百分之七十的几率尿进小便池
even he... Man he just hits the can seventy percent of the time.
- 抱歉 先生 - 不不不 没事 你们继续打扫
- Excuse us, sir. - No, no, no. That's alright. Go ahead.
你们女士们好像聊得很开心
You ladies seem to be chatting enjoyably.
女士们总能聊得这么热火朝天
Girl talk no doubt.
不必介意我
Don't mind me.
艾丽莎
Elisa...
不要碰它
Look, don't touch.
那个可爱的玩意是阿拉巴马产的
That lovely dingus right there is an Alabama Howdy-do
模制握柄 低电流 高电压 用来电击牛的
Molded grip handle. Low-current, High-voltage electric shock cattle prod.
我叫斯特里克兰 是安保人员
Name's Strickland, Security.
弗莱明的手下啊
Fleming's security.
不不 男士一般是便前或是便后洗手
Oh no, no. A man washes his hands before or after tending to his needs.
那这很能说明这个男人的特点
That tells you a lot about that man.
如果便前和便后都洗
If he does it both times,
说明他性格软弱
Points to a weakness in character.
女士们
Ladies
和你们俩聊天非常开心
It was very pleasant chatting with you both.
矮个子的人很刻薄
Short people are mean.
我从来没有遇到过哪个矮个子的好男人
I've never met a short man that stays nice all the way through.
他们都是暗箭伤人的小人
No, sir, mean little backstabbers, all of 'em.
也许地下缺氧还是什么的
Maybe it's the air down there, not enough oxygen or somethin.
救命！他在流血！
Help! He's losing blood!
- 救命！- 快来 快来
- Help! - Come on. Come on.
你觉得俄国佬闯进来了么？ 我可不这样认为
You think the Russians broke in? I don't think so.
如果他们真的闯进来了 杜安的手下会把他们都杀了 亲爱的
And If they did, Duane's meatloaf will kill them all, honey.
有两声枪响 你听见了吗？
It was two shots, you hear 'em?
其实是三声 还有尖叫
Alright three, and that scream.
这里究竟发生了什么啊？
Whatever happens in this place?
你们两个 跟我来
You two. Come with me.
现在就去么 弗莱明先生？ 能让我们先吃完饭吗？
Right now, Mr. Fleming, sir? Any chance we might conclude our dinner?
- 现在就来！- 哦
- Now! - Ugh.
天哪 我们遇到麻烦了 我们遇到麻烦了
Oh heavens to Betsy. We're in a pickle. We're in such a pickle.
只给你们20分钟
You will have exactly twenty minutes,
把实验室给我彻底打扫干净
to render this-this lab immaculate and so on and so forth.
20分钟
Twenty minutes.
好多血
It's a lot of blood.
屎尿什么的 我打扫起来没问题
I can handle piss, I can handle poop...
但是血？ 我怕血
But blood? Mmm. Blood is just something to me.
拿去 帮我擦干净
Here Hon, help me mop it up.
我们越快离开这里越好
The sooner we get out of here the better.
哦！
Oh!
是手指！
It's a finger!
两只手指！
It's two fingers!
好 好 把它们拿走 在这等着
Okay, okay. Put 'em away and just wait here.
我去叫弗莱明过来
I'm gonna get this to Fleming.
残肢在哪儿？
Where are these body parts?
残肢？
The body parts?
我相信你 亲爱的 但是你确定它是活的？
No, I believe you, honey. Are you sure you it was alive?
因为我曾经在马戏团看到过一只美人鱼
Because I saw a mermaid once in a carnival tent.
结果只是一只猴子加了条鱼尾巴而已 当时真唬住我了
And it was a monkey sewn to the tail of a fish. Looked real to me.
好吧 我道歉
Alright, I apologized.
我赶时间
I have a deadline
你知道吗...
You know uh...
玉米片这种零食原本是用来防止手淫的
Corn Flakes were invented to prevent masturbation.
并不奏效
It didn't work.
哦 艾丽丝·费伊的节目开始了...
Oh, Alice Faye just started...
她是个大明星 巨星
She was a huge star, huge.
有一天她终于忍受不了圈子里的那些屁事儿和潜规则
And one day she couldn't take the bullshit, the backstabbing anymore
就头也不回地离开了那个圈子
and she just walked away from everything.
当垃圾来看的话 还算不错 是吧？
Ta-da! It's not bad, is it? For being shit?
听着 你吃完 就上床睡觉
Huh, listen. You eat, you go to bed, you rest.
等我拿到报酬后...
And when I get paid...
我们去吃派！不对 不是我们吃派
We get pie! No, we don't get pie.
是我吃派 你吃你想吃的
I get pie. You get whatever you want.
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
♫ 你不知道 我有多么 ♫
You'll never know just how much
♫ 想念你...♫
I miss you...
♫ 你不知道 我有多么 ♫
You'll never know just how much
♫ 在乎你...♫
I care...
绿色
Green.
- 他们现在想要绿色的果冻 - 但他们之前告诉我要红色
- They want the gelatin to be green now. - But I was told red.
新理念 大势所趋
New concept. That's the future, now.
绿色
Green.
对了 他们还想让这个家庭看起来更快乐点
Oh. And they want them happier- the family.
更快乐 更快乐？
Happier. Happier?
这位父亲看起来像刚发现了传教士式体位(男上女下)
The Father looks like he just discovered the missionary position
贾尔斯
Giles.
好吧...他们还要怎么高兴?
Well uh... What would they supposed to be happy about?
客户想要照片 我说服了他们
The client want the photographs. I sold them on this
- 很遗憾 它是件好作品 - 它确实是 不是吗？
- It's too bad-this is nice work. - It is nice, isn't it?
我觉得它是我最好的作品了
I think it's one of my best.
你撑得住吧？
How are you holding up?
- 在喝酒吗？ - 不 滴酒不沾
- You drinking? - No, not a drop. No.
你离开克莱恩&桑德斯公司之后找到什么工作了吗？
You get any work since you left Klein & Saunders?
你是指我被你辞退之后？
You mean since I was asked to leave by you.
我现在不想谈论这个
We're not gonna get into this now.
我想回来 伯尼
I want to come back, Bernie
再说吧
We'll see.
先把这个搞定了！
Now do this!
艾丽莎！
Elisa!
你在那里面干什么呢？
What are you doing in there?
清洁啊
Cleaning, huh?
听着 亲爱的
Listen, honey.
那位“叉着腰尿尿”先生想要见我们两个
Mr. “I pee with my hands on my hips” wants to see us both.
泽尔达·D·富勒
Zelda D. Fuller.
你们俩认识多久了 泽尔达？
How long have you two known each other, Zelda?
差不多十年了 长官
About ten years, Sir.
你没有兄弟姐妹吗 泽尔达？
No siblings, Zelda?
没有 长官...
No sir...
对于你们这类人来说 这并不常见 是吗?
That's not common, is it? For your people?
我妈妈在生完我之后
My momma died after me.
就去世了
After I was born.
你名字里的“D”是什么意思？
What does the “D” stand for?
是黛利拉 长官
Delilah, Sir.
来自于圣经
On account of the bible.
黛利拉 她背叛了参孙
Delilah. She betrayed Samson.
在哄他入睡之后 剪去了他的头发
Lull him to sleep, cut his hair.
非利士人折磨并羞辱了他
Philistines torture him, humiliate him-
还把他的眼睛挖了出来
Burn his eyes out.
看来我妈妈似乎并没有仔细读圣经
I guess my momma didn't read the good book close enough
那你呢？
And you?
艾丽莎·埃斯波西托
Elisa Esposito.
埃斯波西托不是“孤儿”的意思吗？
Doesn't Esposito means “Orphan”?
两位女士都是来自帕特南的可怜孤儿
Our Lady of Sorrows Orphanage in Putnam.
他们在河边的水里找到了她
They found her by the river in the water.
是你...找到了我的手指？
It was you... that found my fingers?
噢！谢谢
Oh! Thanks.
三个小时的手术
Three hours in surgery.
他们重塑了第一指节 缝合了肌腱
They rebuilt the first phalanx, here, sutured the tendons.
也不知道是否能愈合
Don't know if it's going to take it or not.
上面还沾上了点儿芥末
There was mustard on them.
- 用一个纸袋子装？ - 当时只有这个能用了 长官
- A paper bag？ - It was all we had, Sir.
鉴于她不能说话 大部分都是我来回答
I answer mostly, on account that she can't talk.
她不能说话？她是聋子吗？
She can't? Is she deaf?
是哑巴 长官
Mute, sir.
她说她能听到你
She said she can hear you.
你脖子上的那些伤疤
All those scars on your neck.
原来是伤到了你的声带 对吗？
That's what that it cut your voice box, right?
她说从她还是婴儿的时候就是哑巴了
She said since she was a baby.
谁会那样对待一个婴儿？
Who would do that to a baby?
这个世界充满了罪恶 不是吗 黛利拉？
The world is sinful. Wouldn't you say so, Delilah?
好了 我不废话了
Well, let me say this upfront.
你们打扫那个实验室 然后离开
You clean that lab. You get out.
我们保存在那儿的那个东西 是个耻辱
The thing we keep in there, is an affront.
你知道什么是耻辱吗 泽尔达？
Do you know what an affront is, Zelda?
令人反感的东西？
Something offensive?
没错 告诉你 我把那个...
That's right. And I should know, I've dragged that...
肮脏的东西
...filthy thing
从南美洲的沼泽地里一路拉到这里
out of the river muck in South America all the way here
并且路上我们都相处地不怎么愉快
And along the way we didn't get to like each other much.
现在
Now.
你们可能会认为...那个东西看起来像人
You may think... that thing looks human
用两条腿站立 对吗？
Stands on two legs, right?
但是...神 是按照自己的模样 创造人类的
But... we're created in the Lord's image.
你该不会觉得上帝就是长那样吧？
You don't think that's what the Lord looks like, do you?
先生 我不知道上帝长什么样
I wouldn't know, Sir. What the Lord looks like.
人的样子 泽尔达 上帝长得像人 像我一样
Well, human, Zelda. He looks like a human, like me.
或者像你
Or even you.
我觉得可能长得更像我一点
Maybe a little more like me, I guess.
好 就这样吧
Well, that's all.
霍伊特将军 感谢您的回电
General Hoyt. Thank you for calling me back, Sir.
- 你好点儿了吗？- 是的 将军 好多了
- You feel better? - Oh yes, Sir. Much better.
多亏了止痛药
Pain pills, is all.
- 你被弄断了两根手指头 是这样吗？ - 没错 两根手指头
- You lost two fingers. You wasn't? - Two fingers yeah. He got two fingers.
但是我的大拇指 食指 中指都还健在
But I still got my thumb, my trigger and my pussy finger
听起来你应该没事了 - 是的 将军
Sounds to me like you'll be all right. - Yes, sir, that's right.
期待您日后大驾光临 将军
Looking forward to your visit, Sir.
项目的事还需要您来作决策
Decisions need to be made about the asset.
...位于朴次茅斯市中心地段
...free to locations on Downtown Portermouth.
坐拥未来之地
The Future is here.
去休息吧
Get to rest.
9点30来接我
Pick me up on 9:30.
21点30分 知道了 先生
Twenty one hundred and thirty hours. Yes, Sir.
...买不了吃亏买不了上当
...that's great to buy.
我回来了
I'm home.
我给你做了一个煎蛋卷
I made you an omelet!
- 爸爸！告诉你件事情 - 没有煎饼？
- Hey Dad! Guess what? - No pancakes?
我把家里的箱子翻了个底朝天 就是找不到平底锅
I've gone half through the boxes. I can't find the griddle...
- 我就给你做了个奶酪西兰花煎蛋饼 - 告诉你件事情
- I made you cheese and broccoli omelette, - Guess what?
你怎么样了？疼吗？
How are you feeling? Does it hurt?
- 有一点 止疼药管点儿用 - 告诉你件事情
- A little bit. Pills help. - Guess what?
- 什么? - 我们埋了一个时间胶囊 就在新学校那
- What? - We're burying a time capsule, at the new school.
我想问你
I wanted to ask you.
我们未来真的会有喷气式背包出现吗？
Do you think we'll all have jet packs, in the future?
- 一定会有的 孩子 - 公交车来了
- Believe it son. - Bus is here.
这里是美国
This is America.
再见 爸爸！
Bye dad!
赶紧吃完蛋卷 洗完手到楼上来 亲爱的
Finish your omelet and wash your hands real good and come upstairs, Sweetie.
我还挺喜欢这里的
I kinda like it here.
孩子们喜欢草坪 华盛顿离这里也就半个小时的路程
The kids like the lawn. Plus, DC is just half an hour away, isn't it?
不管怎么说 这里是巴尔的摩 伊莲 没有人喜欢这里
It's still Baltimore, Elaine. No one likes Baltimore.
你知道我是怎么想的吗？
You know what I'm thinking?
我觉得 我需要一辆新车
I'm thinking. I need a new car.
需要一辆新车是吗？
Do you need a new car, do you?
凯迪拉克怎么样 先生？
How about a Cadillac, Mr.?
理查德
Richard.
噢
Oh.
Oh
噢 理查德！
Oh, Richard!
亲爱的 亲爱的 亲爱的 你的手在流血
Sweetie, sweetie, sweetie. Your hand is bleeding.
安静 别说话
Silence. Don't talk. I want you in silence.
安静
Silence.
麻雀窝中睡
The sparrow nests on the window sill.
什么？
What?
麻雀窝中睡
The sparrow nests on the window sill.
魂断猎鹰喙
And the eagle takes the prey.
什么？
What?
鲍勃！
Bob!
艾丽莎！快点！快点！过来
Elisa! Hurry! Hurry! Come on.
快打卡 上帝啊 姑娘
Swipe it. God, girl.
- 你又这样 泽尔达 - 噢 你老人家歇口气吧 约兰达！
- You're doing it again, Zelda. - Oh. Give it a rest, Yolanda!
- 嘿 泽尔达 来一支不 - 吸烟有害健康 杜安
- Hey, Zelda, you want to smoke? - That shit's ain't good for you, Duane.
没错 但是一天不抽心发慌
Yeah. But it feel good.
那倒是真的 不是吗？
It does, doesn't it?
来嘛 艾丽莎 就一支
C'mon Elisa, just one.
来嘛 来嘛 来嘛
C'mon. C'mon. C'mon
别担心那些摄像头
Don't worry about that camera.
我们在休息时间都把它挪开了
We push them off on break time.
嗯哼
Uh- mm
这里是个视角盲点
This here's a blind spot.
我可能要在这里完成一些事情 请将军过来 行吗？
I may have to finish some things in here, fetch the General, will ya?
噢 你想我了？
Oh. You miss me, huh?
我带了一包水果糖
I took a candy break.
你怕这个啊？
This is what scares you, huh?
那我就用这个吧
Jeez, be used to it by now.
又来了！发出那种炸耳朵的声音
There you go again. Making that god- awful sound.
是在哭吗？叫什么？
Is that you crying, huh? Is that what it is?
你疼么？啊？
Are you hurting? Huh?
或者说你很愤怒？
Or maybe you're angry?
或者说你还想再咬我一口
Maybe you'd like to get another bite at me.
啊？来啊
Huh? Go ahead.
你还真敢啊
I can't tell.
你在求饶吗？
Are you begging?
对于我来说 这是我听过最难听的噪音
'Cause to me it's just the worst fucking noise I've ever heard.
艾丽莎？
Elisa?
艾丽莎！
Elisa!
霍伊特将军！欢迎光临！
General Hoyt! Welcome, Sir!
一切都准备就绪 很荣幸您能来这 将军！
Everything's ready. Glad to have you here, Sir!
- 见到你很高兴 小伙子 - 谢谢
- Good to see you, son. - Thank you.
我的老天 就是这个吗？
Good God Almighty, Is that it?
比我想象中要大
A lot bigger than I thought.
奇丑无比
Ugly as sin.
你知道吗 亚马逊土著把这玩意儿当神来供着
You know, the natives in the Amazon worshipped it as a God.
我倒是真看不出来这是个什么神
It doesn't look like much of a God now, does it?
嗯 他们是原始人 将军
Well, they were primitive, Sir. You know they tossed offerings
他们都用些花啊草啊水果什么的当供品
into the water, flowers, fruits, crap like that.
他们还想用弓箭阻止我们石油开采
Then they tried to stop the oil drill with bows and arrows.
他们的下场可不太妙
That didn't turn out too well.
他在流血 怎么回事？
He's bleeding. What happened?
怎么回事？
What happened?
它就是个畜生 霍夫斯德勒 不用管它
It's an animal, Hoffstetler. Just keeping it tame.
“氧气的渗透作用与二氧化碳的置换”
“Oxygen osmosis and dioxide exchange.”
- 为什么要抓来这玩意？- 这个物种 长官
- What the hell we got here, Son? - This creature, Sir
可以在两个独立的呼吸系统之间转换
It can alternate between two entirely separate breathing mechanisms.
- 弹涂鱼也能做到 - 不
- Mudskipper can do that. - No.
如果你想把人送进太空
Look. You want to put a man in space.
他必须要适应 人类不能适应的各种环境
He's gonna have to endure conditions the human body just wasn't made for.
在我们同苏联人的太空竞赛中 这能让我们占上风
This gives us an edge against the Soviets.
他在空气中能存活多久?
How long can it breathe outside the water?
事实上 长官 我们并不了解这东西
Reality, is, Sir. We don't know jackshit about this thing.
我们都知道 苏联人想研究它
Well, the Soviets want it. We know that much.
那些混蛋
Those cockeyed bastards.
他们把狗送进太空 我们可以嘲笑他们
You know, they let them send a dog up in the space and we get a good laugh.
但是紧接着他们 把人也送上去了
Then next thing you know, they send a human up.
一个卫星绕着地球飞 天知道在搞些什么阴谋诡计
A Ruskie, orbiting our planet, doing God knows what?
现在轮到 赫鲁晓夫笑了
Who's laughing now? Krushchev.
他们送狗上了太空 他开心了 接着把一个苏联混蛋送上天
That's it. We let him put a dog in space, he laughs, puts a commie in space
他又笑了 然后他向古巴发射了导弹
he laughs, puts missiles in Cuba.
我们啥也没学到
Have we learned nothing?
长官 我要把它放回水中
Sir. We need to get him back in the water
你看这些科学家 他们就像艺术家 爱上了他们的玩物
See this Scientist, they are like artists. They fall in love with their playthings.
这里 长官 看这里
Now, right here-you see? Along the middle?
这个生物有一块厚实的关节软骨组织 将主要和次要肺分开了
This creature has a thick jointed cartilage separating the primary and secondary lungs.
我说得对吧 鲍勃?
Am I explaining this correctly, Bob?
- 是的 但是我们必须要... - 光拍X光片是不够的
- Yes, but we have to... - It makes the X-rays inconclusive.
- 理论上是的 长官 但我们要先... - 如果我们要打败苏联人
- In principle, Sir, yes but... - If we want to get the edge on the Soviets
- 我们应该 解刨这个东西 - 不 不行
- we need to vivisect this thing. - No, no, no.
- 解剖它 从里到外研究 - 不能这样
- Take it apart. Learn how it works. - No.
不 不行  那不是我们的初衷
No. That would defeat the purpose
长官 他晕过去了 救救他吧
Sir? He's passed out. Please.
把它放进罐子里 给他加压
Put him in the tank. Let him pressurize.
霍伊特将军
General Hoyt, sir!
在任何情况下 您都不能杀死这个生物
You cannot, under any circumstance, kill this creature.
数数这些星星 小伙子 一共有五个!
Count these with me, Son. There's five of them.
这证明我可以 为所欲为
That means I can do whatever the hell I want.
如果你想聊你的研究 我会听你说完
You wanna plead your case? I'll listen to it.
但最后.. 是我下决定
But, end of the day, it is my damn decision.
把那该死的玩意剖开
Crack the damn thing open.
仔细研究研究 结束任务了
Lean what you can and close up shot.
好好休息一下 斯特里克兰
And give yourself a good pat on the back, Strickland.
- 就这样吧 - 谢谢 长官
- You've done it. - Thank you sir.
现在快点开始吧 小伙子
Now hurry up and finish this job, son.
马上开始 长官
Absolutely, sir.
救他出来? 你在想些什么?
Get him out? What are you talking?
不 绝对不行
No! Absolutely not!
因为这是犯法! 这就是原因
Because it's breaking the law! And that's what.
可能连谈论它 都犯法了
We're probably breaking the law, just talking about it.
"他很孤独!" 是么
Oh, he's alone. Oh.
那我们每次去中餐馆吃饭
This mean that... whenever we go to a Chinese restaurant
你都要解救浴缸里的每条鱼么?
you want to save every fish in the tank?
所以他孤单又怎么样呢? 我们都孤单
So what if he's alone? We're all alone.
"它是我见过最孤单的东西"
It's the loneliest thing you've ever seen
好吧 你自己都说了
Well you just said it, right? You just said it.
你说他是个“东西”他是个怪胎
You called it a thing. It's a thing. It's a freak.
我明白你的意思
I can understand you.
冷静 我的天 冷静
Calm down! God, calm down!
好吧 我重复说一遍
Alright. I will... I will repeat it to you.
“我是什么?”
"What I am?
我张开嘴巴 和他一样
I move my mouth, like him.
我发不出任何声音 和他一样
I make no sound, like him.
那又如何?
What does that make me?
现在我的一切 和我所经历的
All that I am, all that I've ever been
都把我 引向他
Brought me here to him.
你用的是“他” 现在改称"他" 了吗?
You see, you're saying "him". It's a "him" now.
这...
It's a...
你打到我了!
You just hit me!
艾丽莎 放开我
Elisa, let go of me.
我听着呢 你从来没打过我！
I'm looking, I'm looking. You've never... hit me!
"当他看向我的时候 他看着我的方式
When he looks at me, the way he looks at me.
他并不觉得我缺少什么
He does not know what I lack.
也不会觉得我是不完整的
Or how I am incomplete.
他看到的我 是真实的我
He sees me for what I am, as I am.
他见到我很快乐
He's happy to see me
每天 每次见到他 都是如此
Every time, every day.
现在 我要么救他
And now I can either save him...
要么让他死去 "
...or let him die.
我要走了 我必须离开了
I'm leaving. I have to... no I have to leave.
艾丽莎 住手! 听我说
Just Elisa, please stop! Listen to me. Just listen to me.
我要走了 我现在必须离开
I have to go! I'm leaving now because this...
艾丽莎 这对我很重要 这是我第二次机会!
Elisa, this is very important to me. This is a second chance for me!
对不起 但我得走
I'm sorry, but I have to go.
当我回来的时候 我们再也不要讨论这个了
And when I come back. We will not talk about this, ever again.
艾丽莎... 够了
Elisa... there's... Alright. Alright.
我们是什么 你和我算什么? 我们没办法!
What are we? What are you and I? What we are? We are nothing!
我们一点办法都没有
Nothing. We can't do nothing!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
但这...它...
But this-this-this is just...
根本不是人类!
Oh god! He's not even human!
我的天
God.
什么
What?
吉尔斯!
Giles!
- 我在等你 - 我知道 对不起
- I've been waiting. - I know, sorry.
没关系
It's okay.
进去谈吗?
We going in?
你把画寄过来就好
You should've just mailed the art.
不 我想亲自给你和你的团队看
No! I wanted to show you it to you and the team and person
这是我的杰作
It's some of my best work.
已经不能更绿了！
And this green as can be!
这个...
It's uh...
现在好像不太合适 也许以后再谈吧
It's not a good time. Maybe later.
好吧 没问题
Oh well, sure, no problem.
你什么时间合适呢 伯尼?
What would be good time for you, Bernie?
这是你画的吗？
You painted that?
是啊
Yeah.
哇！你可真棒！
Wow! You're good!
不过没有照片那样逼真
Apparently, not as good as a photograph.
但也不错了 是吗？
But it's good, isn't it, huh?
反正我画不出来
Pfft. I couldn't paint like that.
来吧 我请了
Here. On me.
给我的？
For me?
我们这没有多少你这样的人 你看起来...
We don't get many like you in here. You seem...
很有教养 我喜欢跟你聊天
very educated. I like talking to you.
事实上...嗯...
The thing is... That's the...
我来这的原因是...
The only reason that I come in here is...
是来聊天的 而且这派味道真不错 是吗？
The conversation. And the pie is mighty fine too, isn't it?
嗯 是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
没加柠檬 但是很美味
It's no key lime. But it's good.
是这样的 我独自一人工作
You know, I work alone. And uh...
我最好的朋友不怎么喜欢聊天
my best friend is not much of a conversationalist.
知道吗？聊天也是在这工作的一部分
You see? That's part of being on the job here.
比如做个调酒师
It's like being a bartender.
你为客人做馅饼 倾听他们的故事 慢慢了解他们
You serve people pie, you listen to their problems. Get to know them.
我想要更了解你
I'd like to get to know you better.
你在干嘛 老家伙？
- What the hell are you doing, old man?
噢 抱歉
Whoa. Oh- oh.
嘿！别坐吧台 把东西打包带走 你们不能坐这
Hey! No- no- no. Not the counter. Take out only. You can't sit there.
你们想要什么 就点好 然后打包带走
You want something, you order, you take it out.
但店里很空啊 吧台...
But it's empty... The counter is-
有人预订了 订了一整天 你不能在这坐
All reserved. All day. You don't sit down.
欢迎再来啊 听见了吗？
Y'all come back now, Y'hear?
你没必要这样跟他们说话
You don't need to talk to them like that.
你也该走了
You should go, too.
别再来了 这里是家庭餐厅
And don't come back. This is a family restaurant.
我找不到其他人聊天了
I have no one.
你是唯一一个能听我说话的人
And you're the only person that I can talk to.
听着
Now.
你想要什么都可以
Whatever this thing is
只要你说需要
You need it.
那么
So...
你只需要告诉我该怎么做就行
You just tell me what to do.
- “所有往事...” - “春日已逝”
- "All those things..." - "As the spring recedes..."
走吧
Let's go!
凯迪拉克帝威 世界上最好的车
Cadillac DeVille. Best car ever made.
v8发动机 390马力 干净利落得像崭新的美元大钞
V8, 390 CID. Clean and crisp like a fresh dollar bill
- 我只是随便看看 - 我只是随便说说
- I am just idling around. - And I'm just talking.
收音功能 加载空调 电动车窗 电子助力刹车
AM radio, air conditioning, power windows, power breaks,
电子助力方向盘 电动座椅调节
power steering, power seats
可更换豪华内饰 有143种选择
All deluxe interior appointment choices. 143 options.
而这辆...
Now this is...
就是个带轮子的泰姬陵
The Taj- Mahal on wheels.
- 我不太喜欢这绿色 - 这可不是绿色 是水鸭色
- I'm not sure about the green. - Oh, it's not green, my friend, Teal.
- 好吧 水鸭对我来说像绿色 - 但它不是 看 这是限量款
- Well, Teal looks green to me. - But it isn't, see? It's a limited edition.
12层喷漆 手工抛光 所有细节镀铬装饰
Twelve coats of paint. Polished by hand. All authentic chrome detailing.
美国百分之八十的成功男士都驾驶凯迪拉克
Four out of five successful men in America drive a Cadillac.
- 这是真的吗？ - 这就代表着未来
- Is that a fact? - This here, is the future.
而你就是那驶向未来的人
And you strike me as a man who is headed there.
- 驶向哪？- 怎么了？未来啊
- Where? - Why? The Future.
你应该拥抱未来 这辆车属于你
You are the man of the future. You belong in this car.
哦先生 这真是辆漂亮的车
Wow, Sir! That is a beautiful car.
要我说 这车开起来一定感觉很好吧？
What can I say? You gotta feel good drivin' that, eh uh?
这绿色多棒啊
And what a wonderful shade of green, huh?
- 是水鸭色 - 水鸭色
- Teal. - Teal.
早上五点 我开车到装载台
So at 5 a.m. I drive my car down the loading ramp.
那时正在交班
And the shifts are changing
我有多长时间？5分钟？我会记住的
How much time do I have? 5 minutes? I'll remember.
5点 5分钟 五- 五 五- 五
5 a.m., 5 minutes. Five- five. Five- five.
你要去移动摄像头
You're going to move the cameras.
我们要对一下表 就像电影里他们那样
And uh. I'm gonna be synchronizing our watches, just like they do in the movies.
哦天 我真为你骄傲 你竟然一点也不怕
Oh God. I'm so proud of you. God. You're just... You're not afraid.
你怕？很怕？别跟我说这些！我已经吓死了！
You are? Very? Don't tell me that! I'm terrified.
这是我最好的作品之一
I think this is some of my best work.
迈克尔·帕克 很好 这名字看起来值得信赖 有点男人味
Michael Parker. A good, trustworthy name. A little butch.
年龄 51岁？
Yes, age fifty- one?
54岁？
Fifty- four.
你这是在说我老吗
It don't have to be rude.
57岁吧
Fifty seven.
我带上假发吧 这样是可行的
I put the hair on, I can pull it off.
我可以穿这件 我应该...
I can wear this. Or I have to uh...
我还有这件 这件好像在说“有工作的男人”
Or I have this. This I think this one says “Working Man”.
还有这件 这件奶油糖色的假领带 有点随意又有点时髦
Now this. This says with butterscotch "tie“ it says casual but with stylish”.
你喜欢这件？我同意 我觉得我们准备好了
So, you like this? I agree. I agree. I think we're ready.
斯特里克兰先生
Mr. Strickland!
莎莉 你能叫埃斯波西托小姐来打扫一下撒掉的水吗
Sally, could you call Mrs. Esposito to clean up this spill?
知道吗 我自己想不明白 你并没什么好看的
You know, I can't figure it out myself. You're not much to look at.
但想想看 我一直在想着你
Go figure. I keep thinking about you.
你说你是哑巴 你是完全不能出声
When you say you're mute, are you entirely silent
还是能咿呀点声响？
Or do you squawk a little?
有些哑巴能出声 不怎么好听
Some of you squawk. Not pretty.
我只是想让你知道 我不怕伤疤
I just want you to know. I do not care about the scars.
我不在意那些伤疤
I don't mind those scars.
我也不在乎你不会讲话
I don't mind that you can't speak, either.
你在我面前跪下的时候
When you come right down to it
我喜欢这样
I like it.
很喜欢
A lot.
有点挑起我的欲望了
Kind of gets me going.
我敢肯定我会让你叫出声来
I bet I can make you squawk a little.
嘿 亲爱的 你还好吗？
Hey, honey, are you okay?
你快点收拾 我想早点回家
You hurry up. I want to be home early.
我的脚痛死了
My feet are killin' me.
我们必须延迟计划
We need to delay the procedure.
进我的办公室要敲门
Knock before you enter my office.
这很紧急！
This is urgent!
出去 敲门我才让你进来 然后再谈事情
Go back out. Knock. Then I'll let you in and we'll talk.
这是规矩 按规矩行事
That's the protocol. Follow the protocol.
进来吧
Come in.
帮我把门关一下好吗？
Will you get the door for me, please?
看见了吗？这就对了嘛 现在我们可以谈事情了
See? That is the way. Now we talk.
我还需要时间
I need more time.
不要让你的挫败感
Don't let the fact that you feel like a loser now
- 和你的求胜心切影响到... - 我没有求胜心切！
- that your competitive tendencies... - I'm not competitive!
我不想毁灭这么复杂且美丽的生物
I don't want an intricate, beautiful thing destroyed.
这个东西死了之后 你学到了东西 我也会离开这里
This thing dies. You learn. I leave. Out of here.
和我的家人一起 在某个安静美丽的城市安定下来
Settle down. My family settles down. Somewhere. Nice. A real city.
这种生物非常聪明 具备语言能力
This creature is intelligent. Capable of language,
能理解情感
of understanding emotions.
苏联人 亚洲佬不也是这样么
So are the Soviets, the Gooks
我们照样杀了他们 不是么？
And we still kill them, don't we?
关键是 这里不是动物园
The bottom line is, this is not a petting zoo.
而且我再也不想在这个鬼地方多呆一秒了
And I don't want to be in this shithole any longer than I need.
你想吗？
Do you?
鲍勃！你想吗？
Bob! Do you?
不 我不想
No, I don't.
嘿 你还在等什么？
Hey, what are you waiting for?
- 你看见艾丽莎了吗？- 快点 泽尔达！
- Have you seen Elisa? - Come on, Zelda!
你是不是在摄像头上动了手脚？在装货码头上？
Did you move the camera? On the loading dock?
你是要把他带到那去吗？带他经过服务隧道？
Is that where you are taking him? Through the service tunnels?
真是聪明啊
That's very smart.
谁在背后指使你的？
Who do you work for?
水的含盐量必须保持在5%到8%
Water must be kept at 5 to 8 percent salinity.
食盐就可以
Table salt will do.
把这个加入水中 三天一次
Mixed one of these in this water. Every three days.
粗蛋白也是必需成分
Raw protein diet is a must.
五分钟之后 我在装货码头和你会合
In five minutes, I'll meet you at the loading dock.
灯会熄灭 所以做好心理准备
The lights will go out, so be prepared.
斯特里克兰先生 距离活体解剖还有12小时 而且...
Mr. Strickland, Sir. 12 hours to the vivisection of asset. And uh...
请在这里签名
I need your signature here, please.
停车 不要动
Hold it, right there.
- 迈克尔 帕克 是你本人吗？ - 是的
- Michael Parker. Is that you? - My whole life.
你疯了吗？
Are you out of your mind?
不要这样做 艾丽莎！别这么做！
Do not do this, Elisa! Don't do this!
- 那是什么？是什么工具车？- 是洗衣工吗？
- What's that? What's that vehicle? - Laundry man?
但是没有登记过！
But it is not scheduled!
- 长官！- 和我在装货码头会合
- Sir! - Meet me at the loading dock.
- 长官！你要干... - 去找支援
- Sir! What do you... - Get back up.
- 先生请下车 - 哦天哪我不擅长处理这种情况
- Step out of the vehicle, Sir. - Oh God, I'm not good at this.
下车 快！别让我再重复一遍
Out of the vehicle. Now! I will not say it again.
- 请别向我开枪 - 下车！
- Please don't shoot me. - Get out!
你们还在等什么？我们快没时间了
What are you waiting for? We're out of time!
现在下车！
Get out now!
必须要走了！快点！
We have to go! Hurry!
哦！我们要下地狱了！
Oh! Woman we gon' burn in hell!
快点 快推！推！
Come on, push! Push!
我发誓我不是故意不下车的 我一直不会弄机械的这些东西...
I swear, I'm not doing this on purpose! Mechanical objects and I don't get along...
她在码头等你！
She's waiting for you at the dock!
- 快走！- 好的 马上
- Go! Now! - Okay. Hold on.
那个男人是谁？他刚才好像杀人了
Who's that man? I think he just killed someone!
哦我的天哪！我的天哪！我的天哪！
Oh my God! Oh my God! Oh my God! Oh my God!
准备好了吗？准备好了吗？
Are we ready? Are we ready?
他真是美啊
He's so beautiful!
是我撞的吗？
Did I do that?
我真的不擅长这个
I'm just not good at this.
快走！快走！
Move! Move!
不！
No!
盐？你在说什么？盐？
Salt? What are you talking about, Salt?
艾丽莎！
Elisa!
以色列“炸弹”
Israeli “Popper.”
你闻到镁的味道了吗？
Do you smell the magnesium?
俄国人恨死犹太人了 但还是用他们做的这些小玩意
The Russians hate the Jews, but they can't get enough of their gadgets
他们怎么进去的？
How did they get in?
伪造的身份证件 假牌照等等之类的
Forged ID. Fake plates. And so on and so forth...
他们还动了码头上的主摄像头 先生
And they moved the main video camera on the dock, Sir.
好吧 没必要告诉别人 我还有24小时来解决这件事
Well, no one has to know. We got 24 hours before I bounce out.
我已经上报了
I called it in?
你上报了？
Did you called it in?
刚出事的时候我就
The moment it happened, I...
斯特里克兰先生
Mr. Strickland, Sir.
怎么了
What is it, Sally?
长官 霍伊特将军在等您的电话
Sir, General Hoyt is on the phone.
那个两栖人对我们来说就像太空狗一样珍贵 斯特里克兰
That thing was our Space Dog, Strickland.
你知道的
You know that.
先生 我会把他抓回来的
Sir, I'm gettin' it back.
我没有-我不能再往坏处想了 先生
I don't-I can't be in a negative frame of mind, Sir.
所以你感觉很好么？
So you're feeling good?
我有信心 把他抓回来
Feeling strong. Getting it back
你能搞定的 必须把它抓回来 为了我 你能办到的下伙子
You can get it done. You're gonna get it done. For me, Son. For me.
你计划那天放他走吗？
Is that when you're planning on releasing him?
十号？
On the tenth?
如果降雨推迟了呢？
So what if the rains are late?
水道会怎么样？
What happens with the canal?
好吧
All right.
那是什么？
What's that?
让我看看
Let me see it.
那是给我的吗？
Is that for me?
这很好 你继续保持
That's good, keep it up.
看起来你还什么都不知道呢
Lookin' like you don't know anything.
如果他们来找我的麻烦了 请上帝保佑我
Lord help me if they ask me if I do.
我不太会撒谎
I am not a good liar.
对布鲁斯特除外
Except for Brewster.
为了维持婚姻我撒了很多谎
Takes a lot of lies to keep a marriage going.
所有人员请注意
All personnel.
请准备好你们的身份证和门禁卡
Prepare to present your ID and entrance card.
保密措施已经...
Security measures has been...
这是怎么了？
What in the...?
全体人员请注意
Attention. All personnel.
请准备好你们的身份证和门禁卡
Prepare to present your ID and entrance card
你让我们惹上大麻烦了！
You got us in trouble!
在我看来 我们面对的一个受过高度训练的组织 先生
In my opinion, we are looking at a highly trained group, Sir.
长官 我觉得是特种部队之类的
I'm thinking, conceivably, Sir. Special Forces and so on and so forth.
苏军特种部队？
Red Army Special forces?
八九不离十
Conceivably.
一个受过高度训练 经费充足的精英组织
A highly-trained, well-financed, elite group.
高效率 残忍的 工作极其精准
Highly efficient, ruthless, clockwork precision.
潜入行动不到五分钟就结束了 先生
Infiltration took less than five minutes, Sir.
我怎么都觉得要花上十分钟才能完成行动吧
I can sure the estimate of this Strict Force of at least 10 minutes.
你一直是一个人呆着吗？
Have you always been alone?
你有过朋友吗？
Did you ever have someone?
你知道你发生了什么吗？你知道吗？
Do you know what happened to you? Do you?
因为我不知道 我不知道我身上发生了什么
'Cause I don't. I don't know what happen to me.
我不知道
I don't know.
我照镜子 唯一能认出的就是那双眼睛了
I look in the mirror, the only thing that I recognize are these eyes.
长在一个老男人的脸上
In this old man's face.
有时我觉得我生的太早 有时又觉得生的太晚了
And sometimes I think I was either both too early or too late for my life.
可能我们俩都是老古董吧
Maybe we're both just relics.
先生 我找到他们了
Sir? I got them.
泽尔达 艾丽莎 请进
Zelda, Elisa. Come in.
看来在事情发生之前 你们俩已经打卡下班了
Looks like you two, punched out before the incident.
所以
So.
如果你们知道关于一些泄露物的信息
If you know something about what transpired here.
你们有义务去报告所有的细节
It's your obligation to report any detail.
无论这些细节多么的微不足道
No matter how small or trivial it may seem.
“微不足道”的意思是“不重要”
"Trivial" means "unimportant".
我没发现有什么反常的 没有
I didn't seem nothin' out of the ordinary. No.
微不足道的也没有 你看 我的脚伤了
Or trivial. See? My feet were hurting...
那你呢？
What about you?
她什么都没看到
She didn't see anything.
霍夫斯德勒  霍夫斯德勒博士
Hoffstetler. Dr. Hoffstetler.
你看到他进出过这个实验室吗？
Did either of you see him coming in or out of the lab?
他在这儿工作 不是吗？
He works there, doesn't he?
我说的是另一个意思
I mean in a different way.
做一些不寻常的事情
Doing something different.
你是说微不足道的那种事么 没有 先生
Something trivial? No sir.
我在这儿干什么？
What am I doing?
我居然询问你们这些家伙
Interviewing the fucking help...
洗衣服的
The shit cleaners...
扫厕所的
The piss wipers.
你们两个走吧 离开这儿
You two, go ahead. Leave.
你跟我说什么？
What did you say to me?
- 她说什么？-我不知道
- What did she say? - I didn't catch it.
- 他说什么？- 她说“谢谢你”
- What is she saying?! - She is saying "Thank you".
下一个
Next.
我们要做的只有一件事了
There's only one thing left to do.
“志愿者”
"Volunteer".
不要！不要！
No! No!
我想早点回家
I want to get home early.
最近布鲁斯特很爱生气...
Brewster has been in a bad mood lately...
圣主耶稣！
Holy Jesus!
你躲在女士更衣室干什么？
What are you doing standing in the shadows of the women's locker room??
他们可能一直在看着我 这儿应该没有摄像机
They may be watching me, and there are no cameras here/
理由不错嘛
For good reason.
你在这个时候见我们是有何贵干？
What if you caught us in an inconvenient moment?
- 我需要知道他是否安好 - 它很好
- I need to know that he is alright. - He is.
- 什么时候放它走？ - 会尽快的
- When will you release him? - Soon.
当雨水将连接大海的水道填满的时候
When the rain fills the canal that flows to the sea.
如果你需要任何帮助
If you need anything.
放了它 赶紧的
Release him. Soon.
她说什么？
What did she say?
她说 “你是个好人”霍夫斯德勒博士
She said, you're a good man, Doctor Hoffstetler.
我叫德米特里
My name is Dimitri.
很高兴认识你
Honored to meet you.
嗨 哑巴！有你的电话！
Hey, dummy! Phone call for you.
很紧急
It's urgent.
不用担心我 我很好 相信我 我没事
Don't worry about me. I'm fine. Believe me, I'm fine.
它跑了 这不是他的错
He ate Pandora, it wasn't his fault.
他是一个野生动物
He's a wild creature.
我们不能要求它做其他任何事情
We can't ask him to be anything else.
艾莉莎 去找他 快去！
Elisa, Go find him. Go. Go!
快去！
Go!
你很幸运
You're lucky.
我一直在努力保持清醒
I stayed awake as long as I could
但毕竟我不是年轻人了
But I'm not even a young man anymore.
他还好么？你确定么？
Is he alright? You sure?
你要去哪儿？ 别 别
Where are you going? No, no.
好的 别别 别和小猫呆在一起
Ok. No, no. Don't play with the kitties.
别跟它们在一起玩
Don't play with the kitties.
我不生气
I'm not angry.
你确实这么做了 没关系 我觉得这不卫生
You did that. That's okay. Ooh. I don't think that's sanitary.
可以了
Enough.
有趣的家伙
Interesting guy.
全体人员请注意
All personnel.
请准备好你们的身份证和门禁卡
Prepare to present your ID and entrance card.
你找我？
You wanted to see me?
那个调查进行得怎么样了？
How's it going? The investigation?
噢 进展不错
Well, we have a promising lead.
是么？
Really?
那挺好的
That's good to hear.
你从加尔维斯顿调过来
You joined us in Galveston.
- 但你之前在哪里工作呢 霍夫斯德勒？- 博士
- But where were you before, Hoffstetler? - Doctor.
- 什么？- 请叫我
- Excuse me? - Doctor.
霍夫斯德勒博士
Hoffstetler.
这是规矩
Protocol.
- 我之前在威斯康星大学麦迪逊分校 - 那就对了
- Wisconsin. Madison. - That's right.
你放弃了终身教职 对吧？
You gave up a tenure track position. Didn't you?
为了我们
Gave it all up...
什么都不要了
For us.
那么 我想你现在已经准备好离开我们了 对吗？
I suppose you're getting ready to leave us now, then, huh?
如果找不到那个生物的话 是的
Only if the creature isn't found.
你想什么呢？ 你真以为我们能找到它？
What do you think? You think we will find it?
噢 你说过你们有进展了
Well, you said you had a lead.
确实
I do.
亲爱的 你在傻笑什么？
Why you smiling, hon?
别这副表情好嘛
Stop looking like that.
你俩干嘛啦？
What happened?
怎么可能？
Why?
他？
How?
他怎么做到的？
他他他他有那东西？
Does he? Have a?
这样
Mmm.
再这样打开 就长出来了嘛
永远别以为男人很单纯
Never trust a man.
即使他那里光秃秃空荡荡平平无奇
Even when he looks flat down there.
我刚报名参加了一个人类学课程
I just signed up in anthropology.
我们全班都要去亚马逊雨林
We're gonna go have classes in the Amazon Jungle...
- 在南美洲 - 南美洲？
- in South America. - South America?
哦天哪 那可得大清早就出发
Oh man. You have to get off early in the morning
那地方很远的
That's a long hike.
- 我们要待在那儿 - 我们？
- We're gonna stay down there. - We are?
哦 不 你该不会也要去吧
Oh no. You're not coming along too.
尝尝这个吉利丁冻糕
This is a gelatin parfait.
你会爱上这个味道的
You will love it.
爸爸 我们能看《伯南扎的牛仔》吗？
Dad, can we watch Bonanza?
那对你们来说太暴力了 你知道我今天在想什么吗？
Bonanza is much too violent. You know what I was thinking today?
我们带着孩子
We get the kids a P-U-P-P...
怎么回事？ 这水都涌进我的电影院啦
What is going on? I've got water pouring into my theater.
有四个付了钱的观众 我还得给他们退票
I have four paying customers. I can't afford a refund.
可能是某个管道的问题 我会处理的
It's probably a pipe. I'll take care of it.
- 修不好就别住这里了 - 我会修好的
- If you don't fix it. No more renting. - I will fix it.
艾丽莎！
Elisa!
我的天哪！
Dear God!
艾丽莎！
Elisa!
我在擦干我的头发
I'm toweling my hair.
我的头发！
It's my hair!
还有 看看我的手臂 那些伤口
And... and... look at the arm. The wound.
好像从来没有过一样 太神奇了
As if it was never there. Look at them.
你说过 人们把他当成神一样供奉着
You said... He was worshipped like a god.
他是上帝吗？ 我不这么觉得 他可是吃了一只猫
Is he a God? I don't look to him as a God. He ate a cat
哎 我真不知道
So I-I don't know! I don't know!
我们得让他多留一阵子
We have to keep him around, awhile
就一阵子
A little while.
喂？
Hello?
你的水 长官
Your water, Sir.
- 还有 长官 霍伊特将军找你 - 不 别接通
- And, Sir, General Hoyt. - Uh-mm. Uh-mm.
告诉他我不在 我会打给他 总之别接进来
Tell him I'm not in, tell him I will call him back. Don't put him through.
不是来电 长官 他已经在你办公室里了
No, Sir. He's in your office.
现在我们唯一关心的就是那个研究对象
At this point our only concern is the asset.
你找到它了吗？
Do you have it?
还在找 长官
Still in the wind, sir.
那可不好
That won't do.
嗯 我知道
Yes sir. I know.
你认识我多久了 长官？
You've know me for how long, Sir?
- 十三年了 釜山战役就认识了 - 是的 长官
- Thirteen years. Battle of Pusan. - Yes, sir.
一个男人尽其一生都是有信仰 忠诚 做事高效的
A man is faithful, loyal, efficient all of his life. All of it
还很有能力
And he is... useful.
而他期望...
And he expects...
他当然想要一定的回报
He has certain expectations in return.
但是 他失败了
And then... He fails.
一次 仅此一次
Once. Only once.
那会导致什么？
What does that make?
会让他变成失败者吗？
Does that make him a failure?
当一个男人完成任务 来证明他自己 将军
When is a man done, Sir? Proving himself?
他是一个好人
A good man.
一个体面的人
A decent man.
体面？
Decent?
一个体面的人不会把事情搞砸
A man must have the decency not to fuck up.
这是一种体面
That's one thing.
真正的体面
That is real decent of him.
另一种体面嘛 其实并不重要
The other kind of decency. It doesn't really matter.
我们摒弃它 不是因为我们没有这种品质
We sell it. But it's an export.
而是因为它对我们没用
We sell it 'cause we don't use it.
36小时以后 这一切就结束了
36 hours from now, this entire episode will be over.
你也一样会完蛋
And so will you.
我们的世界将会出现一个破洞
Our universe will have a hole in it with your outline.
你会去另一个世界
And you will have moved on to an alternate universe.
一个糟透了的世界
A universe of shit.
你会被淹没在那文明里
You will be lost to civilization.
未诞生
And you will be unborn.
未成形
Unmade.
未存在
Undone.
所以 去挣些真正的体面吧 小伙子
So, go get some real decency, Son.
然后收拾好这堆烂摊子
And unfuck this mess.
36个小时
Thirty-six hours.
36小时
送快递 你送快递的！
Deliver. You deliver.
你就是个送快递的！
That's what you do. You deliver, right?
对吧！
Right?!
你
You'll...
永远
never...
不会知道
know...
我有多么
Just how much...
多么
I've...
爱
loved...
你
you...
你 永远
You'll...
不会知道
Never know...
我有多么
Just how much...
♫ 在乎你 ♫
I care...
♫ 就算我不告诉你 ♫
And if I tried
♫ 我也没法掩饰我对你的深情 ♫
I still couldn't hide my love for you.
♫ 你得知道 ♫
You ought to know
♫ 我只是不告诉你 ♫
For haven't I told you so
♫ 你走了 把我的心也带走了 ♫
You went away and my heart went with you
♫ 我为你祷告 ♫
I speak your name in my every prayer
♫ 我该怎么向你证明  我有多么爱你 ♫
If there is some other way to prove That I love you
我无法向你诉说
I swear I don't know how.
你不会明白的
You'll never know
你怎么会明白
If you don't know now
艾丽莎
Elisa.
怎么啦 宝贝？
What is it, my honey?
情况不妙啊
This isn't good.
我要把霍夫斯德勒博士喊来了
I'm going to call Dr. Hoffstetler
你今晚就得放走它了 宝贝
You got to release him tonight, honey.
我会回来帮你的
I'll come back and help you.
他要出来了
He's coming out.
呃
Ugh.
先生 恕我直言
Sir, If you don't mind me saying.
您看起来不太好啊
You don't look so well.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你闻到了吗
Can you smell that?
是你的手指 都黑掉了
I think it's your fingers. They are black.
哦他来了 狗屁博士
There he is, Doctor fucking shitbird.
先生 你这说的太难听了
There's no call for cursing, Sir.
给我滚出来 这车归我了
Get out of the car. I'm taking it.
- 这是我的车 快他妈给我滚出去
- This is my car. - Get the fuck out.
- 这可是我的车 - 你听不见我说话嘛？
- Out of my car? - Did I stutter?
- 哎妈 幸好 斯特里克兰 - 你又讲俄语了 鲍勃
- Strickland, thank God! - You were speaking Russian, Bob.
- 你叫什么名字 - 霍夫斯德勒
- What's your name? - Hoffstetler.
哎呀 这时候就没必要说假话了
Oh no. Don't lie. You don't need to.
你肚子上可是中了一枪
You took a bullet to your gut.
你离死不远了
You're dead.
我要突击队里所有人的名字 军衔和藏身位置
I need the names, ranks and locations of the entire Strike Team.
突击队？
Strike Team?
抢走我们研究对象的那伙人
The ones that took the asset.
这个糖 虽然很便宜 但我从小就爱死它了
This candy. It's cheap candy. I love it ever since I was a kid.
有些人中意那些 看上去更高级的零食
Some folks favor more sophisticated snacks
牛轧糖和那些破玩意儿
Nougat center and all that fu-fu shit.
但我不喜欢
But not me, Bob.
我就爱吃这个
This is it for me.
我觉得紧张的时候
Now. Sometimes, if I'm feeling anxious
我就大嚼一番
I just bite right into it
但平时我还是会慢慢的
But mostly, I take my time.
将它一点一点吃完
I make it last.
他们的名字 编号和位置
Names, ranks and location of the strike team.
名字 编号！给我快点！
Names! Ranks! Now!
没名字
No names
没编号
No ranks
他们...
They...
早就逃之夭夭了
They just clean.
知道了布鲁斯特 我会准备晚餐的
Alright Brewster. I'm gonna fix you dinner
然后我要出去一下 去帮个朋友做点事
and then I'm going to run out for a little while and help a friend.
- 做什么事？- 就是帮朋友啦
- Help with what? - Helping a friend.
泽尔达
Zelda.
门
Door.
你他妈的连门都不能帮着开一下吗
Well, You could well help me answer the door, Brewster!
你就坐在离门十尺的地方！
You're sittin' right there just ten feet away from it.
我背疼啊 婆娘 你去就是了
My back is acting up, woman. You move.
背疼 背疼 你就知道背疼
Your back. Your back. Always your back.
斯特里克兰先生！
Mr. Strickland!
你怎么在这？
What are you doing here?
- 那个男人是谁？ - 它在哪？
- Who's that man, Zelda? - Where is it?
- 你在说啥？- 你把它带到哪儿去了？
- What are you talking about? - Where did you take it?
泽尔达
Zelda.
在实验室里
The thing in the lab.
哪儿？
Where is it?
- 什么在哪里？- 给我坐下！
- Where is what? - Sit down!
哎呀先生我不是有意的
I'm sorry, Sir.
要是我知道 我肯定会告诉你的
If I knew anything I would surely tell you.
我还没告诉你参孙的故事
That story about Samson.
是如何结束的
I never told you how it ended.
在非利士人狠狠折磨 还把他弄瞎了之后
After the Philistines torture him and blind him.
于是他向上帝祈求力量
Samson asks God for the strength he needs
就在最后一刻
And at the last minute, he is spared.
上天
And the Lord...
给予了他所要的力量
Gives him his strength back.
最后一次
One last time.
他抓住了神庙的柱子
And he holds the columns of the temple
然后用他有力的胳膊把柱子推了个粉碎
with his powerful arms and crushes them
整个庙都塌了 把非利士人也给埋了
And he brings the whole building down on the Philistines.
他是死了 但他也把那些狗屁玩意儿全部操翻了
He dies. But he gets every single one of those motherfuckers.
那就是他的愿望
That is his will.
现在
Now.
你现在明白这个故事的意思了么？
Do you know what that particular story means?
对于我们来说 黛利拉
For us, Delilah
它告诉我们 如果你有什么瞒着我的话
It means that if you know something you're not telling me,
你终究会告诉我的
you're gonna tell me. Either.
无论是要等到我
Either before or after...
把你家毁掉之前
I bring this particular temple...
还是之后
down upon our heads.
那个哑巴把它从实验室偷走了
Gal stole that thing right out the lab!
不管它是什么
Whatever it is.
你去找吧
You go took it.
我听我老婆
I heard my wife.
打电话的时候讲的
Talking on the phone about it.
非常感谢你  富勒先生
Thank you very much, Mr. Fuller for your assistance.
- 你做了什么? - 泽尔达!
- What have you done? - Zelda!
我得提醒他们! 他去找她了
I got to warn her. He's going after her
女人 你不许这样做
You will do no such thing, Woman.
你管她做什么? 她犯法了
Why you worry about her? She broke the laws
闭嘴  布鲁斯特! 你闭嘴!
Shut up, Brewster! You shut up!
这么多年你一言不发
For years, you don't talk
你可以继续闭嘴了
and now you can't shut your mouth.
去你丫的 布鲁斯特!
Damn you Brewster!
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand.
说什么都没用 你永远明白不了的
You couldn't understand. Not if you tried your whole life
- 嗨? - 吉尔斯 是你吗?
- Hello? - Giles, that you?
- 是的 - 让艾丽莎接电话
- Yes. - Put Elisa on the phone.
是泽尔达的电话
It's Zelda.
艾丽莎 亲爱的 如果你能听见我的话  弄点声音
Elisa, honey, make a sound in the phone if you can hear
好
Okay, good.
他去找你了
He's coming for you.
你现在得走了 带上那个东西
You got to go now and you go to take that thing with you.
怎么了? 艾丽莎!
What? Elisa!
妈的
Dammit.
我们得下车了!
We have to go!
你在哪?
Where are you?
你他妈的到底在哪?!
Where the fuck are you?!
你好啊
That's nice.
我从不会失手
I do not fail.
我做到了
I deliver.
艾丽莎!
Elisa!
不
No.
我的天
Fuck.
你确实是个神
You are a God.
关于她的故事
If I told you about it
我要怎么说呢
What would I say?
说他们从此以后幸福的生活在一起?
That they lived happily ever after?
我相信是这样的
I believe it is.
他们相爱
That they were in love
永远相爱
That they remained in love.
我确定这是真的
I'm sure that's true.
当我想起她时 想起艾丽莎...
But when I think of her, Elisa...
只有一首诗 浮现在我的脑海
The only thing that comes to mind is a poem
那是几百年前一对情侣的甜言蜜语...
Whispered by someone in love, hundreds of years ago...
“无法描述你的形状”
“Unable to perceive the shape of You"
“我感觉到你围绕着我”
"I find You all around me."
“因为你的存在 我满眼都是你的爱意”
"Your presence fills my eyes with your love"
“它让我的心变的柔软”
"It humbles my heart"
“你无处不在”
"For you are everywhere"